Okay, so, yeah.
2 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
I have a couple of L three outs here. This is all in a single tenant, this is all my VRF two, but we're just gonna be focusing on this WAN BGP L three out. So let's pretend this BGP L three out is like your fusion L three out. And then never mind that this L three out is EIGRP, but let's pretend this EIGRP L three out is actually the one facing your AWS outpost. So we're gonna pretend like it's BGP for the purposes of this demo. So the the goal is we're gonna be learning some networks on this EIGRP L three out and we want to average.
3 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Ties them out via this BGP L three out. So over on the EIGRP side, I have a pair of leaf switches and and this would I'm just using regular like leaf switches in this case, but this would apply for a remote leaf as well. So the configurations I can be different from this perspective.
4 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
It's a little slow on me today, but I have leaf 2201 leaf 2202. And those two guys are connected to see this N3K So I have this N3K with a ok with the ERGRP adjacency, neighborship whatever so 1201 1202.
5 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Those are those two leaf switches that are 2201 2202. So on this guy, I've been, I have a loopback address or a loopback interface, show run hello 50.
6 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Yeah 50. And so I just have a couple of secondaries in here. So I got a/twenty four, I got a series of/twenty sixes, you know, in the 51 range. So if you could pretend like this is the ten range or something and then 5200 one/twenty six.
7 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
And so I'm just advertising those five BGP up ERGRP to 20 122-012-0202. So, without going deeper into that setup, what we want to do is then advertise it out of this BGP L three out. And so this is on a different pair of leaf switches. Again, sorry, this is a little bit slow on me this morning.
8 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
So, 1201 1202 different pair of leaf switches. Those are appeared to this quad three here. That is this guy right here. So this is another N3K now if I check its routing table, oh here's what I'm currently here's what I'm currently learning. So we just have like one BGP I routes. I believe this is one of my bridge domains or something like that. So what do we do to get.
9 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
These networks advertised over. So that's where we can use our transit routing configuration on the egress L three out. So essentially, as long as that route is learned by the ACI fabric in that particular VRF, then we can create a route map to.
10 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Match on that and then advertise it out. So there's a couple ways of doing it. I think for what you want to do with minimal administrator intervention is create a route map here. So I've already created these ahead of time. So I have this export five X route profile here and the route profile.
11 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Files in ACI, they map basically to what you're familiar with in like NXOS, like route maps and prefix lists, it's just the names are a little bit different, so we have a context here, so order zero, just have a single entry. Go ahead and open that up, just show you what I have configured here. We're gonna say permit just like you would do like normally on the CLI. We'll do a match rule, so in this match rule here, we're going to match on, of course, the.
12 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Networks that we want to advertise. We'll go ahead and open that up. And you get a lot of options here like you can match on community terms and stuff, but we're just matching on prefixes here. So what I've done already is like that 50 slash 204I was showing and then I also have, cut.
13 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
You know, all of these routes here if I go back, all these guys, I'm basically matching on everything here. So like these four/twenty sixes make up a/twenty four. So that's why I have the/twenty four here. I'm doing effectively a Le 32. So if you enable the aggregate option.
14 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
This is gonna allow you to natch on like those smaller networks. So I haven't applied this yet, but you know, that's what the configuration looks like. So to actually apply this, I can go to my external EPG and I want to talk about the other options.
15 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
You have, I just think this is probably gonna be the most effective for you, but what you can do is then go down to route control profile. Again, this is on the external EPG and then you can apply that.
16 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
That route profile that I was just showing, that will hit the little plus sign here, get our dropdown, export 5xI just export all I might get to that in a bit, but we're just gonna focus on the one I showed you.
17 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Export five X And then make sure you change this from default. So you can also do like import filtering, but what we want to do is basically export you know by our networks that we want to export out to our you know fusion.
18 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
So we'll hit update there. Now we'll hop back over to this is my external BGP router and let's pick this routing table after making that configuration. So then that's matched on.
19 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Those networks that are coming up through my EIGRP L three out. Now I think what I could do here just to demonstrate that this isn't gonna require, you know, additional administrative intervention here is let's go ahead and like maybe add the next.
20 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
The next network in this range in like the 52 range, so, here, and let's see what we can do.
21 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
And then that shows up on the other on the BGP L via the excuse me, BGP L three out because I have that route map that is.
22 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Matching on, that whole range. I have that Le 32 entry in my, in my route profile. So in a nutshell, that's why I wanted to show you that it is possible to do this and you can be decently granular in what you want to export.
23 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
Okay let me stop there, yeah. Any questions? Yeah, yeah. Because in this export are you spotting the all the 50 range that you create? In our case that we are already sending some routes out that belongs to the real ACI, right? I need to include that one and the new one from another side. What about the sport order you have?
24 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Sorry kidd.
25 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
Yeah, because we have already some somenets that are inside ACI, the 1065 that belongs really to the to the lab, to the lab environment that we are very dice also to the future, right? There's not only is not going to be only the AWS sonnets that we are going to create new one, but because.
26 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
We already have some other name.
27 "Aian Denis" (793721856)
That are inside the ACI. Those are internal APs that belong to the that is associated with the L three out, right? So you advertise.
28 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
Those via that method, right? Exactly if I create the roadmap, I need to include that also in the roadmap, NO?
29 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
So are those bridge domain subnets.
30 "Aian Denis" (793721856)
Is that what we mean, correct?
31 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Oh yeah, you don't need.
32 "Aian Denis" (793721856)
You don't need them here. These are internal apts.
33 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Right? Yeah, in fact, you can still advertise your bridge domain subnets like you normally do in addition to this or in fact, you have some flexibility here. You can actually use this to advertise, to even just use this to advertise both your bridge domain subnets and your like transit routes that you're learning from AWS. So.
34 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
It's up to you. You can keep your existing.
35 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Configuration at all.
36 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
Into it essentially. In other words, it has the, the bridge domain with the subnet there. We don't have to include it in this route export.
37 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Yeah advertised.
38 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
And through the.
39 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
Through the L three out because it's part of the subnet and the.
40 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Yes, so in fact, I think I have a bridge domain like that. I just need to find the right one.
41 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Yeah, I want to say I already have a bridge domain here.
42 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
In 171610I think that's the one we saw. Yeah, so like I already have a bridge domain subnet and that's advertised I believe through the traditional method.
43 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
But I definitely don't have this included in the route map that I was showing. Yeah I'm doing this the like traditional way where you associate to the L three out and then you advertise the you have the little advertised externally checked box. So you could do this in addition to the route map that I was showing or you could include everything in the route map.
44 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
In fact, NO.
45 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
There's one more thing I can show you with it, but hopefully that answer.
46 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
This is your question. Yeah, that that answers and what do you have in the include.
47 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
All that you have. Yeah, so what I wanted to show is what you can also do, I I'm more of a fan of being more specific on what you want to advertise, but you could just do essentially a hail Mary here and advertise everything so you could do a quad zero/zero LEE 32 and that would literally advertise everything in the.
48 "Aian Denis" (793721856)
In the VRF. What about what about did you know the AS number coming from the, from the outputs, right? So anything learned from them you wanna trust, right?
49 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Yeah, NO, now can we use that to export actually options here for match rules.
50 "Aian Denis" (793721856)
No, before when you, when you get ok the right control rule, yeah, open one, you have aspath regex. I'm assuming we can.
51 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
For any community going from them that you can we create your fear.
52 "Aian Denis" (793721856)
Yeah, I'm saying, I mean, if you want to be granular and not coming back here all time, like, if you have a cider that you can't point, you have a cider that summarizes every subnet that they will be using, you can, you can use a prefix list, right? But if you have a an AS number click on on the plus hour JT that match path regex terms, see what else do we have?
53 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Yeah, so it's just a simple regular, well, I say simple.
54 "Aian Denis" (793721856)
So it's a you you can create a regular expression that includes the the autonomous number coming from them, right? That's not that's what i'm assuming that goes.
55 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
It's not something I've done myself. I might need to take a look at the, here, let's take a little bit of a side side journey here. As anyone seen the L three out white paper, it's a very good resource we can try to see there. I think the examples I've always seen has just been ciders, sorry I'm a little zoomed out there.
56 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Yeah, so you can do pre pending, but can we match with AS? I don't see why not. It's just not something I've done specifically myself. That's the only hesitation I have.
57 "Aian Denis" (793721856)
Okay.
58 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Right. So.
59 "Aian Denis" (793721856)
My point, my point if it if it is possible, then that that will future proof any CIDR they use, right? Downside if you're truly trusting everything coming from them. If they advertise something they shouldn't, you're gonna inject that into your enterprise IDP, right? But if that's what you guys want, this is what.
60 "Aian Denis" (793721856)
So flexible, because right now if you have exciter let's say the more they decide to whatever they run out of IPs and they want to expand the sider, they have to come to you A extend unless you do what JP just said, they basically use a prefix list that is quad zero ELE 32, right? Which pretty much includes everything.
61 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Yeah, so what I can do is I can test that in my lab actually so we can see if we can match on the AS I just need to set up another BGP L three out. I unfortunately, I only have one BGP L three out.
62 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
And I was using that EIGRP one which works well with Cider, but I'd need to process up another BGP one. So I can, I can verify that, I just need probably a little bit of time. When, when would this configuration.
63 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
Shouldn't be implemented. No, I, we already implemented for this.
64 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
That are.
65 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
Okay but now they are start talking about creating the the VPC and they are requesting new new segment. I'm gonna say NO NO this is going to be adding new segment every week and I forgot. I had to put this thing away that is going to be easy.
66 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Yep yep gotcha. Okay, yeah, so do you have a preference like do you want me to test the AS match option or would you prefer the cider option, which.
67 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
That's what I showed here. No, it's it's I we can work with this one, put the quad zero, and we trust everything or I don't think that I can or we can trust the ASA number, but it's the only, if they put the wrong ASA number and forget it, it's not going to bring up the BGP because we are matching ASA, you know?
68 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Yeah, so just a little word about the quad zero, so let me show you what that looks like. I mean, it's, it's gonna be everything in that VRF so I could flip that over.
69 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Where'd you go? Oh, yeah, this is, that was my bad. So if you go too fast, I set that as an import policy, my bad. Let's make that export.
70 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Yeah, Yeah so I mean you you get a lot more, but I have like my other, you can see here actually these are additional bridge domain subnets, so it's just going to show that you can also use this to match on bridge domain networks as well, but within ACI.
71 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Now, that's actually tunable, so if you want.
72 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
Okay.
73 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Oh, actually that's just the routing policy. Yeah, anyway, so just be aware of that is it can also advertise the bridge domain subnets. So this is a pretty broad.
74 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
Stroke. Okay, and in the BGB we say AWS I I don't need to.
75 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Do any configuration, right? Yeah, you wouldn't need to, as long as ACI is learning those routes, that's all we care about, and then so this is it's gonna match on those routes.
76 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
On the egress border leaf switches. So, one troubleshooting step would be if on the fusion side you're not seeing those routes come in, then on your egress border leaf switch facing fusion, I have to get my VRF name.
77 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
You can just do a simple show IP route of your F two Yeah so if you're not seeing your network on fusion, then run the equivalent of this commander.
78 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Your egress borderly switch and then make sure it's in it's in that borderly switches local routing table for that VRF.
79 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
Okay.
80 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Okay. Alright, I'll send over some additional documentation, but that's, that's kind of it, in a nutshell, I guess one little final point is you might also see something called.
81 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
And I don't mean to cause confusion here, it's just in case you see this in documentation. When we're talking about transit routing, probably the more common option is to do export route control subnet here. This is where like you configure your external subnet for the external EPG for like policy application.
82 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
But the problem with this is you would have to match on those subnets explicitly. So that's why I went with the route policy approach. So that's what you'll see in that document that I'll send you, but this is more I think of what you would want to do.
83 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Okay.
84 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
Alright, I think that's pretty much everything I had. Any questions? Let, let me show you the configuration that I have in another.
85 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
In the.
86 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
Sure case I can get to the ACI.
87 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
Okay.
88 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
Sorry, are you there? Hey, leave me.
89 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
The.
90 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Okay.
91 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
It was my machine that they put new dates.
92 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
Yeah, I got new updates. I don't know every time that get the dates.
93 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
No? I thought.
94 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
There they are two layer three outs that they start with OP or you show the.
95 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
Alright.
96 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
My question.
97 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
Five, not working.
98 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
Okay.
99 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
Okay. In the lab, the layer 3 h configuration for the Opus devices.
100 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
That one, the service link. No, NO, the service link, the one in the bottom, NO. Okay, the APG, anyone.
101 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
Okay.
102 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
Okay, I have to specify the sonness.
103 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
There in the EBE. So the way that you're gonna be able to get that granular well here let me back up a bit. So what I was showing is actually it starts over on the left hand side. So you see that where it says route map for import.
104 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Export route control. It's on your far left like in the blue column. Yeah, that one. So that's where I had created my route policy. So yeah, you right click that, create that route map for import and export route control. Yeah, you can get so you can type in a name here. So what I had in my environment was I typed in like export-5x.
105 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
You can call whatever you like.
106 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
For.
107 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
You can say like exports maybe AWS routes or LP routes. This is going to be the route.
108 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
That is coming from AWS, right? Yeah, and this should be placed on the L three out that's facing fusion or the equivalent thereoff in this.
109 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
Environment. It was aL3 out regular? Is it doesn't.
110 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Fusion this one. Oh, ok. So the rate, ok, so the L three out called L three out, that's the one facing fusion. In which case that's where you want to create.
111 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
This actually, so it's always on the egress L three out. Okay yeah yeah but my question is in in the layer three out that face the AWS devices in the in the APG, in the standard APG I have to specify also the song that I'm going to receive there.
112 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Oh, sorry. Yes, sorry. You're absolutely correct. Sorry my mind was in a routing space. Yeah, you do need to make sure that's accounted for here. So you need extra external subnets for the external EPG here cause this is telling ACI from a contract perspective.
113 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
Those networks exist via this L three out. Okay, any way I need to look.
114 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Manual configuration then, right? Yeah, so here it's just longest prefix match. Now in this VRF, do you already have a.
115 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
10/zero? Yes, and the future.
116 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Okay yeah. So we only recommend having that wild card on 1L3 out in the L three out EPG in the VRF. So in which case you just wanna, you'd wanted to find something LPM that matches, you know, everything in AWS. You can have multiple.
117 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
All entries as well like you're doing here. Yeah but ok that that is my second point because then I have to create.
118 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Get it manually here every time that I have the Well, not necessarily as long as you can account for that in your longest prefix match, like what CIDR you're putting in there, then you don't need to touch this again. So, are like e.g. are they all coming out of the ten dot.
119 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
Zero.zero.zero is like/eight.
120 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Networks space? Yes, that is coming everything here. Yeah, so like you could do something like that. You could do a ten 00/eight or you can make it, you know, even more specific than that. But just as an example, so in which case, as long as it falls within that range, you know.
121 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
We need to come in here and do a manual change. Okay, and in this case we put it aggregated true and now we can put it a/summary/thirty two.
122 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Here. You won't, you won't need to do it for that network type. You won't need to do it for that scope, the external subnet for the external EPG. That is really It's not, yeah, this one actually doesn't impact routing. This is more for contract stuff actually. So this is just to ensure ACI is going to permit.
123 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
Best traffic.
124 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
Okay, but if you put that one you had to create a contract because you put it anything they had to talk to that's.
125 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Sending had to be in the contract. Yes, however it depends on how we're applying policy in the CRF. So are you already.
126 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
Using contracts here? I think we put one yes.
127 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Yeah, and the this VRF is the VRF enforced.
128 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
This.
129 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
There won't be RF here in the, in the lab. Is it enforced though, so meaning like contracts are actually going to apply. So if you click right on lab.
130 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
Yeah, so we got.
131 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Faster than my lab. I'll get I'll say that. Yeah, policy tab.
132 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
Yeah, you're enforced. Okay ok yeah we import all the traffic to be in the contract because if NO anything can be.
133 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
The yep so contract rules would still apply in this case. So to permit the traffic, you would also need to ensure you had to.
134 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
Contract like between those L three out EPGs. Exactly, that was my point. I mean we put it down a bit. Yeah.
135 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
Yeah, I we already I think we already have the contract in the standard in that standard I believe but I was thinking more in the.
136 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
In in the center that's the contract.
137 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
The we are we are still working with the service link, the one in the world.
138 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
Okay.
139 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
The layer three out.
140 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
What do you need is the the OPBGB service link layer three out, the one that one any of the they have a controller singing, they have a associated control.
141 "Aian Denis" (793721856)
Okay.
142 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Yeah, so what you could do is go to one of those. You might need to check both, but you can yeah click on that one, then hit the contracts tab.
143 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
On the top.
144 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Okay.
145 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
Yeah, so this is providing consuming looks like.
146 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Allow any. And then you would need to make sure that like that contract is, you know, provided/consumed over on the, that the one facing future.
147 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
The L three outs.
148 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
One, let's see. Yeah, it's also why.
149 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
Oh, here, start the creation.
150 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
This one oh ok ok yeah.
151 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
So it looks like it's applied there. By the way, this is kind of off topic, but I noticed you're doing a lot of providing consume in both directions on every EPG. Just as a heads up that and eat up your TCAM space on the switches, just are you keeping it now.
152 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
Eye on your TCAM utilization?
153 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
I'm sorry on what? Are you taking, are you monitoring your T CAM usage on your switches?
154 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
EPGs, but.
155 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
No, sorry this is a little off topic, it's just I noticed you're that providing consuming the contract on everything. Can you go to operations at the top?
156 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
And then capacity dashboard and.
157 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
Have leaf capacity in the top right.
158 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
Is capacity.
159 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
Top right. Oh yeah.
160 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Up right. There you go. It's the same. Alright, NO, you're doing ok. So i'm taking a look at that policy cam column. So what that is is basically the hardware memory that gets used to enforce access control lists. That's essentially what we're doing when we.
161 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Apply contracts in hardware, it's NO different than access control lists like from NXOS and iOS. When you provide and consume a contract, it's not the most efficient way of doing things, but you are well under, you're well within like your policy cam space. So you know real in general, we would.
162 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Recommend just doing a single provider single consumer type of thing. However, since you don't have too many EPGs at the moment, it's not eating up too much face. I would just say keep an eye on this, but, you know, if we start exceeding the scale, then might need to reevaluate how the contracts are being applied. But again, you're only like.
163 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
5 %.
164 "Aian Denis" (793721856)
So it's kind of like a non issue right now. No, NO, it's.
165 "Gordon Montgomery" (793697280)
Yeah these are these are these are pretty manual.
166 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
Sorry.
167 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Granular.
168 "Aian Denis" (793721856)
And and they're providing and consuming the same contracts from the vast majority of the, of the EPGs or some exceptions were doing on four sevens, but.
169 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
No, not too.
170 "Aian Denis" (793721856)
Anyway. So what do you use in five or I would have loved them to for them to use these.
171 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Things like any or or you know preferred group membership.
172 "Gordon Montgomery" (793697280)
Oh so you're saying 5 % is, is NO worry. What at what point do we worry?
173 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Well, it's kind of like the normal bounds. The, the thing is it's better to start early. Maybe we can talk about this sometime on like what options there are for more efficient, like permit any configurations.
174 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
To answer your question, like, once you start getting up to like, you know, 75 80 %, it's kind of like, you know, CPU utilization, it's like you don't really wanna be around that level. It's not gonna break though until you hit a hundred percent. It's one of those like.
175 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Once you hit a hundred percent utilization, then that means we're not able to program memory properly. So a hundred percent really is your upper bound, but you're at 5 %. So you're on the extreme low end. So this is, I would say not a major concern right now, but it.
176 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
There's an opportunity to implement best practices? What I need to focus most on the policy can, does the.
177 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Or and everything. What you want to keep an eye on everything to be sure this is like a monitoring dashboard, but just for the purposes of your contract configuration.
178 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
It's policy can that you want to keep an eye on. This one, ok. Let's see one of one of the, the now.
179 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Then.
180 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
I'm sorry I don't mean to like raise the alarms or anything. It's just just a heads up. Oh NO, I curiosity, this one has more, more contract and more everything, you know.
181 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Oh, we got very good, you know. Yeah, I got.
182 "Aian Denis" (793721856)
Couldn't maybe scroll.
183 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
Yeah, but just to be sure but yeah these are all pretty low numbers as one of the two that we build.
184 "Aian Denis" (793721856)
And now and then we have all the almost all the contract there. Yeah, with the jt's point there are we're not anywhere near, but if we get to a point there are constructs within ACI that can help us and I brought this up back when we did the 1st implementation with Rob, but Rob did an analysis and saw this number. So yeah, There's.
185 "Aian Denis" (793721856)
They don't, they don't want to overcomplicate, but there are there are contracts within ACI that allow to make this contracts configuration a lot simpler, right? Like the ones mentioned before BCNE or preferred group to membership, those things. You can group EPGs in this data umbrella and would mean that that would translate to a single let's say you have.
186 "Aian Denis" (793721856)
20 EPGs that will form the same, then now you don't have 20 entries in your T camps, you only have one then you reference that group as a bigger umbrella kind of deal, right? But, yeah, we can certainly look look into that and to also to get this point and answering Gordon's question, the difference between these this memory, right?
187 "Aian Denis" (793721856)
This is not this is not CPU. So CPU usually when you hit that threshold of 7580 it's concerning because any process could could eat whatever is available here it's it's something it's something the consumption will be extracted enforced by what you guys configure, right? And to Kt's point, the upper bound rate is a hundred percent. I mean, if you are at 95 % obviously.
188 "Aian Denis" (793721856)
That you should deploy new contracts or deploy new consumption and and and and providing relationships to contracts, right? But you the switch will perform perfectly fine, right? It's when you hit that on percent mark where you.
189 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Will not be able to configure any more of these entries, right?
190 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
Yeah, exactly. Yep.
191 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
Okay, anyway, we learned something that's the most important.
192 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Yep. I'll send some documentation on I'll send some documentation on the routing configuration, the transit routing configuration as well as just like some of the options you have for like more optimal contract application, but you guys are really.
193 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
Low levels right now, so it's not a concern. Okay, thank you for letting us know and.
194 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
And where do we have to look? Yep. All right. Sorry to sidetrack everyone, but yeah, maybe back over to the L three outst.
195 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
Then I I put the 1000 slot eight there in the layer three out facing AWS and the road.
196 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Up in the layer three out with future, right? Yep yep correct. In fact, yeah, you already have those export route control subnets. So you're base, you're basically doing the same thing. It's just the way I showed you with that route map option is a little bit more flexible because then you can use the aggregate option. Okay.
197 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Okay, sounds good.
198 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
All right. Yeah any questions on this? No.
199 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Let me open a chain to to do the configuration. Sounds good. And I'll send out the recording later today. Yeah, and Jonathan, not to pick on you, but I just wanted to follow up from yesterday.
200 "Jonathan Pellon" (322194176)
Did you have any questions on the service graph stuff? No, I actually haven't been able to do much and look at it today, but I do know that it worked yesterday. Was able to do some postman magic, right? Where we got the changed to allocation. Everything was working out.
201 "Jonathan Pellon" (322194176)
I'm so proud, I'm so proud that you said that. Well I mean.
202 "Aian Denis" (793721856)
Kudos to, to, to soccertainties, you know? Yeah, yeah, yeah. It was, it was.
203 "Jonathan Pellon" (322194176)
And so I added that Dom physical, you know, I did that it wasn't working, but then now it's working, NO problem. We have it with a static allocation. Can you check the L four, make sure it's still up socketies I think it is, but in any case everything seems good, you know? I think later on I'm gonna try and add that secondary port channel for the fusion just to have it in the configuration.
204 "Jonathan Pellon" (322194176)
Cause I I did, what I did was I took my two vpcs that, you know, just so I didn't have problems with configuring vpcs. I I took two VP, two nodes that would become the vpcs for the firewall and all that stuff and.
205 "Jonathan Pellon" (322194176)
And, have them, I have them there, right? So that I can pre configure this everything and then I'll pack up one of the nodes and just, you know, send it to the ship, but it was, Yeah, go to go to the, go to deploy graph instances.
206 "Jonathan Pellon" (322194176)
So yeah there we are. There we are. Awesome. So as soon as I provide and consume the other one, which is for the ITV we should see that.
207 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
That one there as well, so we're good.
208 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
Okay. Thanks, Jonathan and Thanks we added the the EPG today in.
209 "Jonathan Pellon" (322194176)
Jonathan, whatever we missing. Yeah.
210 "Aian Denis" (793721856)
Sure.
211 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Oh. All right.
212 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
Anything else we need to discuss before we close out the bridge? No.
213 "JT Stamm" (2137663488)
Sounds good and NO rest of the thing. Alright, I'll send the recording later on today along with some documentation and.
214 "Manuel - NCL" (2775377664)
We'll give everyone maybe about 8 min back here. Thanks everyone. Thanks.
215 "Eng. Socrates Romay, MBA." (3421360384)
Thank you so much. Thank you. Bye bye. Thank you.